A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- Series X. Secretary of Finance Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)., Extent: 37904 emails.
  - Series X. Secretary of Finance Electronic Files, Subseries G. Connie Biggs Email, 2007-2010 (bulk 2008-2009).
    Subjects include: state budget; budget reductions; agency correspondence (Accounts, Planning and Budget, Taxation, Treasury); financial presentations (Senate Finance Committee, House Appropriations Committee, Joint Money Committees, etc.); bond sales; revenue letter; monthly revenue reports, Secretary of Finance weekly reports; Governor's Advisory Board of Economists (GABE); Governor's Advisory Council on Revenue Estimates (GACRE); Fort Monroe Federal Development Authority; Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP); American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA - 2009 federal stimulus); Commissioner's Advisory Group (CAG); Fort Monroe Federal Development Authority; audit reports; and the Productivity Investment Fund (PIF).
    Correspondents include: Janet Aylor, Joan Baker, Jeanine Black, Janie Bowen, Ric Brown, Craig Burns, Don Darr, Cintra Davis, Jerry Edwards, Kimberly Frazier, Manju Ganeriwala, Stephen Harms, Tim Kaine, John Layman, Melissa Mayes, Brian Shepard, Faye Straub, Dan Timberlake, Wayne Turnage, Michael Tutor, Jody Wagner, William Watt, William White, Evie Whitley, and Marcella Williamson.
  - Series X. Secretary of Finance Electronic Files, Subseries H. Cintra Davis Email, 2006-2010.
    This subseries contains 833 emails in two PST files: CDAVIS.PST and KaineLibCDavis.pst. Cintra Davis served as Special Assistant to the Secretary of Finance from May 2006 to January 2010.
    - CDAVIS.PST, 2007-2010.
      The CDAVIS.PST contains 571 emails sent and received by Cintra Davis between December 2007 and January 2010.
      Subjects include: bonds; budget, legislation, weekly report, constituent correspondence, Governor's Advisory Board of Economists (GABE); Governor's Advisory Council on Revenue Estimates (GACRE); American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA - 2009 federal stimulus); and university applications for Level II status under the Higher Education Restructuring Act.
      Correspondents include: Connie Biggs, Ric Brown, Craig Burns, Jerry Edwards, Manju Ganeriwala, Gary Janak, H. Lane Kneedler, John Layman, Barbara Reese, Brian Shepard, Lisa Tortorella, Lynda Tran, Wayne Turnage, David Von Moll, and Jody Wagner.
    - KaineLibCDavis.pst, 2006-2009.
      The KaineLibCDavis.pst contains 262 emails sent and received by Cintra Davis between November 2006 and October 2009.
      Subjects include: agency correspondence, bonds, budget, legislation, Governor's Advisory Board of Economists (GABE); and Governor's Advisory Council on Revenue Estimates (GACRE).
      Correspondents include: Tracy Clemons, Scott Cummings, Jim Fisher, Mark Haskins, Gary Janak, Lynn LaBarre, John Layman, Emily Ward, and William Watt.
- Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, 2003-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)., Extent: 13208 emails.
  The Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files series documents the electronic communication of the office during the Kaine administration. This series contains 13208 emails in eight (8) subseries. Subseries have been designated for: A. Scott Kasprowicz Email; B. Barbara Reese Email; C. Ralph Davis Email; D. Ralph Carr Email; E. Nicholas Donohue Email; F. Alleyn Harned Email; G. Melanie Roberts Email; and H. Kevin Farrelly Email. There are 570 privacy protected and confidential emails that are restricted from public access per Code of Virginia, 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to: attorney-client communications. The Library did not receive any email files from Secretary of Transportation Pierce Homer. However, email messages send by Homer may be found in the email files of other members of the Kaine administration.
  During the administration of Governor Timothy Kaine, the Secretary of Transportation had the responsibility of developing and implementing Virginia's transportation program, including policy and financial oversight for seven agencies and a variety of major transportation projects. The seven agencies were Commonwealth Transportation Board, Department of Motor Vehicles, Department of Transportation, Department of Rail and Public Transportation, Virginia Port Authority, Department of Aviation, Motor Vehicle Dealer Board, and Virginia Board of Towing and Recovery Operators.
  The Secretary of Transportation email contains a large number of acronyms. The following list, while not comprehensive, represents the majority of acronyms used by this secretariat. AASHTO=American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials; APMT=APM Terminals North America, Inc.; ARCA=Amended and Restated Comprehensive Agreement; CAPRA=Capital Reserve Account; CE=Categorical Exclusion; CLRP=Financially Constrained Long-Range Transportation Plan; CTF=Commonwealth Transportation Fund; DCMP=Dulles Corridor Metrorail Project; DIAAH=Dulles International Airport Access Highway; DTR=Dulles Toll Road; ERW=Early Retirement Window; FFGA=Full Funding Grant Agreement; FFIS=Federal Funds Information for States; FHWA=Federal Highway Administration; FIS=Financial Impact Statement; FRANs=Federal Reimbursement Anticipation Notes; FTA=Federal Transit Administration; HMOF=Highway Maintenance and Operating Fund; HOT Lanes=High-Occupancy Toll Lanes; HRTA=Hampton Roads Transportation Authority; HSIP=Highway Safety Improvement Program; LOI=Letter of Intent; LONP=Letter of No Prejudice; MPO=Metropolitan Planning Organization; MWAA=Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority; NVTA=Northern Virginia Transportation Authority; NVTC=Northern Virginia Transportation Commission; OST=Office of the Secretary of Transportation (Federal); PMO=Project Management Office; PMP=Project Management Plan; PPTA=Public-Private Transportation Act of 1995; PRTC=Potomac and Rappahannock Transportation Commission; RAP=Resource Allocation Plan; REF=Rail Enhancement Funds; STP=Surface Transportation Program; SYIP=Six-Year Improvement Program; TIFIA=Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act; TIP=Transit Improvement Program; TMP=Transportation Management Plan; TPOF=Transportation Partnership Opportunity Fund; TTF=Transportation Trust Fund; USDOT=United States Department of Transportation; VDOT=Virginia Department of Transportation; VIT=Virginia International Terminals; VPA=Virginia Port Authority; WERDA=Water Resources Reform and Development Act; WMATA=Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; WTA=Workforce Transition Act; and WWB=Woodrow Wilson Bridge.
  Pierce R. Homer was reappointed Virginia's Secretary of Transportation by Governor Kaine on 5 January, having also served as Secretary of Transportation under Governor Warner. Prior to his appointment as Secretary, Homer served as Deputy Secretary of Transportation with functional oversight of the Virginia Department of Transportation, private partnership programs, and technology investments. As Deputy Secretary, he worked with the transportation agencies to develop and implement uniform cost and revenue estimating, debt management, and accountability measures.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries A. Scott Kasprowicz Email, 2006-2007.
    The subseries contains 123 email messages in one PST file: KASPROWICZ.PST. Scott Kasprowicz was Deputy Secretary of Transportation from January 2006 to April 2007. The KASPROWICZ.PST contains 123 emails sent/received by Scott Kasprowicz between January 2006 and May 2007.
    Subjects include: Department of Aviation (purchase of a new plane); Dulles Rail; and transportation projects (Route 15 and Route 50).
    Correspondents include: Randall Burdette, James Carr, Pierce Homer, Dennis Morrison, Kathleen Penny, and Trip Pollard.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries B. Barbara Reese Email, 2007-2010 (bulk 2007-2009).
    This subseries contains 8068 emails in one PST file: KaineLibbreese.pst. Barbara Reese served as Deputy Secretary of Transportation from July 2007 to January 2009. She served as Deputy Policy Director and Legislative Director for Governor Kaine from January 2009 to January 2010. For additional Reese email, see Series II. Policy Office Email, Subseries H. Reese was in charge of the day-to-day management of the Dulles Rail project (as of 25 February 2008).
    The KaineLibbreese.pst contains 8068 emails sent and received by Barbara Reese between April 2007 and January 2010. There are 566 privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to: attorney-client communications.
    Subjects include: legislation, transportation funding, I-95/395 PPTA (HOT lanes); I-495 Capital Beltway HOT lanes; REAL ID; ARRA (2009 Federal stimulus); Downtown Tunnel/Midtown Tunnel/MLK Extension; Public Private Partnerships (PPP); Route 460; Dulles Toll Road/MWAA; Dulles Corridor Metrorail Project; Gray v. Virginia Secretary of Transportation, et al (transfer of the Dulles Toll Road to MWAA); HB 3202 implementation (transportation funding legislation - includes abusive driver fees); Virginia Port Authority; Port of Virginia; Craney Island eastward expansion; Virginia Department of Rail and Public Transportation (DRPT); Virginia Department of Transportation (VDOT); Crescent Corridor Memorandum of Understanding; and Route 460.
    Correspondents include: Jeffrey Allen, Nancy Auth, Charles Badger, James Bennett, Tom Biesiadny, Jerry Bridges, Deborah Brown, Jamie Brown-Porter, Craig Burns, Reta Busher, Sam Carnaggio, Young Ho Chang, Karen Chappell, Marc Cheatham, Whitt Clement, Larry Cloyd, Ashley Colvin, Clyde Cristman, Ed Crooks, Scott Cummings, Betsey Daley, Ken Daley, Ralph Davis, Suzette Denslow, Nick Donohue, David Ekern, Jeff Florin, Melinda Glazer, Kevin Greenlief, Dick Hall-Sizemore, Lynette Hammond, Lynn Hampton, Mark Haskins, Thomas Hawthorne, Gordon Hickey, Corey Hill, Dusty Holcombe, Frank Holly, Pierce Homer, Tim Kaine, Jeff Keever, Quintin Kendall, Malcolm Kerley, Barbara Klotz, Michael Kulper, John Lawson, John Layman, Chris Lloyd, Alfonso Lopez, Brenda Madison, Charles Massie, Jo Anne Maxwell, Stephen McCullough, Declan McManus, John Milliken, Jennifer Mitchell, Ronaldo Nicholson, Rodney Oliver, Anne Oman, Kevin Page, Shiva Pant, Jeff Parker, Thomas Pelnik, Ann Perdue, Peter Peyser, Jennifer Pickett, Steve Pittard, Jason Powell, Stuart Raphael, Margaret Redford, Larry Roberts, Andrew Rountree, Mark Rubin, Brian Shepard, Winnie Shi, Chuck Shimer, Delacey Skinner, D.B. Smit, George Spakouris, Philip Sunderland, Jim Taylor, Letitia Thompson, Matthew Tucker, Wayne Turnage, David Von Moll, Jody Wagner, Brian Walsh, Richard Walton, and Molly Wood.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries C. Ralph M. Davis Email, 2009-2010.
    This subseries contains 692 emails in one PST file: RDAVIS.PST. Ralph M. Davis was Deputy Secretary of Transportation from January 2006 to January 2010.
    RDAVIS.PST contains 692 emails sent by Ralph Davis between July 2009 and January 2010.
    Subjects include: transportation; 2035 Surface Transportation Plan (STP); Commonwealth Transportation Board (CTB) VTrans2035 Subcommittee; and 2008 Transportation Performance Trend Report.
    Correspondents include: Debra Bayles, Linda Carpenter, Scott Cummings, Don Darr, Nick Donohue, Kevin Farrelly, Katherine Graham, Robin Grier, Pierce Homer, Larry Jones, and Mary Lynn Tischer.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries D. James D. Carr Email, 2003-2007.
    This subseries contains 1757 emails in one PST file: jcarr.pst. James D. Carr was re-appointed as Assistant Secretary of Transportation by Governor Kaine in January 2006 and served until June 2007. Governor Mark Warner appointed Carr to this position in July 2003.
    jcarr.pst contains 1757 emails sent and received by James D. Carr between June 2003 and June 2007.
    Subjects include: Virginia Capital Trail (VCT); Virginia Capital Trail Foundation (VCTF); creation, design, funding, and construction of VCT.
    Correspondents include: Phil Baker, Jack Berry, Ron Chwojdak, Whittington W. Clement, Emmanuel Darko, Jennifer Debruhl, Nicholas Donohue, Harold Dyson, Doug Ellis, Suzanne Ellison, Holly Eve, Samuel Hayes, Steven Hicks, Pierce Homer, Judith Ledbetter, Jim McCarthy, Mark Merhige, Diane Mitchell, Anthony Opperman, Kevin Page, James Paul, Emily Peter, Barbara Reese, Conrad Scott, Philip Shucet, Pete Shudtz, Susan Simmers, and Marvin Sowers.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries E. Nicholas Donohue Email, 2007-2010.
    This subseries contains 716 emails in two PST files: KaineLibNDonohue.pst and NDONOHUE.PST. Nicholas Donohue was Assistant Secretary of Transportation from July 2007 to January 2010.
    KaineLibNDonohue.pst contains 715 emails sent and received by Nicholas Donohue between March 2007 and January 2010. One attorney-client email in this PST file is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. NDONOHUE.PST contains one email sent by Nicholas Donohue on 15 January 2010.
    Subjects include: Virginia Capital Trail; legislation; VDOT access management regulations; Chapter 527 Public Advisory Committee (regulations on transportation and land-use planning); transportation legislation and regulations; Secondary Street Acceptance Requirements (SSAR); electric vehicle charging stations (EVCS) at certain state rest areas; and revision of Virginia Impact Fee Guidebook.
    Correspondents include: Philip Abraham, Tom Biesiadny, Morgan Butler, Judith Cronauer, Pierce Homer, George Homewood, Dan Lysy, Ted McCormick, Chris Nelson, Pat O'Hare, Trip Pollard, Harrison Rue, and Beth Weisbrod.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries F. Alleyn Harned Email, 2006-2007.
    This subseries contains 1563 emails in one PST file: 2007LibAHarned.pst. Alleyn Harned served as Special Assistant to the Secretary of Transportation from January 2006 to May 2007. Harned was often copied on email to Secretary of Transportation Pierce Homer. (See Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries F. Alleyn Harned Email, 2006-2009).
    2007LibAHarned.pst contains 1563 emails sent and received by Alleyn Harned between April 2006 and May 2007.
    Subjects include: constituent correspondence; Dulles Corridor Metro Project; I-77 tunnel, transportation agency weekly reports (Department of Aviation, Department of Motor Vehicles, Department of Rail and Public Transportation, Virginia Department of Transportation, Motor Vehicle Dealer Board, and Virginia Port Authority); and Secretary of Transportation weekly reports.
    Correspondents include: Chuck Armstrong, James Carr, Vivian Cheatham, James Cline, Sarah Crenshaw, James Davidson, Ralph Davis, Lillie Doggett, Susan Edwards, Linda Ford, Bill Foy, Pearl Gordonel, Bruce Gould, Judi Hepper, Pierce Homer, Keith McCrea, Linda Patrick, Jennifer Pickett, Barbara Reese, Barbara Scorsome, Renee Simms, Mattie Smith, Sande Snead, Luella Spellman, Vicki Thacker, Christina Thompson, and Olyn Warfield.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries G. Melanie Roberts Email, 2007-2008, 2010.
    This subseries contains six emails in two PST files: KaineLibMRoberts.pst and MROBERTS.PST. Melanie Roberts served as Special Assistant to the Secretary of Transportation from June 2007 to January 2010.
    KaineLibMRoberts.pst contains four emails sent and received by Melanie Roberts between July 2007 and June 2008.
    MROBERTS.PST contains two emails sent by Melanie Roberts on 15 January 2010.
    Subjects include: constituent correspondence.
  - Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries H. Kevin Farrelly Email, 2009.
    This subseries contains 283 emails in one PST file: KFARRELLY.PST. Kevin Farrelly was 2009 Governor's Fellow for the Secretary of Transportation. After his fellowship ended in July, he worked on special projects for the transportation secretariat until December 2009.
    KFARRELLY.PST contains 283 emails sent by Kevin Farrelly between June 2009 and December 2009.
    Subjects include: Transportation Performance Report; and VTrans2035.
    Correspondents include: Ralph Davis, Nick Donohue, Katherine Graham, Pierce Homer, Jennifer Pickett, and James Ponticello.
- Series XII. Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)., Extent: 1369 emails.
  The Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry Electronic Files series documents the electronic communication of the office during the Kaine administration. This series contains 1369 emails in three (3) subseries. Subseries have been designated for: A. Robert Bloxom Email; B. Charles Green Email; and C. Tracy Campbell Email. There are four privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information includes attorney-client privilege and personnel records. The PST files for Bill Dickinson, Deputy Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, and Shauna Chavis, Executive Assistant to the Secretary, were both empty. However email messages sent by Dickinson and Chavis may be found in the email files of other members of the administration.
  The Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry was created in 2004 to give a cabinet level voice to the number one industry in Virginia. The secretariat facilitates the growth and viability of the industry, provides a strategic balance in progressive economic development and utilization of natural resources, and positions the agriculture and forestry industries to be major contributors to the revitalization of Virginia's rural economy.
  During the administration of Governor Kaine, the Secretary oversaw and provided policy guidance to two agencies- the Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and the Virginia Department of Forestry. In addition to the agencies, the Secretary oversaw the Virginia Agricultural Council and the Virginia Marine Products Board. The Secretariat of Agriculture and Forestry also provided policy guidance and direction to its agencies regarding the conservation, protection and development of Virginia's agricultural and forest resources, as well as consumer protection.
  - Series XII. Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry Electronic Files, Subseries A. Robert S. Bloxom Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    The subseries contains 1294 email messages in one PST file: RBLOXOM.PST. Robert Bloxom served as Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry from December 2004 to January 2010. Prior to his appointment, Bloxom served in the Virginia House of Delegates (R-Accomack County) from 1978 until his retirement at the end of 2003. During his time in the legislature, Delegate Bloxom served on the Agriculture, Labor and Commerce, and Chesapeake and its Tributaries committees, and served a term as Chairman of the multi-state Chesapeake Bay Commission.
    RBLOXOM.PST contains 1294 emails sent by Robert Bloxom between January 2006 and January 2010. There are four privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information includes attorney-client privilege and personnel records.
    Subjects include: information about agricultural issues such as swine flu, poultry diseases; budget issues; legislative files; drought; state agencies within secretariat; and Virginia Horse Center.
    Correspondents include: Don Blankenship, Gena Boyle, Preston Bryant, Shauna Chavis, Aneesh Chopra, Jeff Corbin, Bill Dickinson, Jerry Edwards, Carl Garrison, Todd Haymore, Tim Kaine, Bill Leighty, Elaine Lidholm, Nikki Rovner, Brian Shepard, Delacey Skinner, and Wayne Turnage.
  - Series XII. Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry Electronic Files, Subseries B. Charles Green Email, 2005-2006.
    This subseries contains 17 emails in one PST file: Cgreen.pst. Charles Green served as project manager for specialty agriculture production, part of Governor Mark Warner's Virginia Works initiative. Launched by Governor Warner in 2004, Virginia Works was an economic development initiative for rural Virginia that focused on keeping existing industries competitive and strong, using existing resources to attract new businesses, and strengthening communities through building the type of infrastructure needed to compete for new jobs. As project manager, one of Green's responsibilities was identifying all potential loan sources to support specialty agriculture ventures and meet with a variety of stakeholders in the agribusiness community.
    Cgreen.pst contains 17 emails sent and received by Charles Green between October 2005 and February 2006.
    Subjects include: Virginia Works initiative.
    Correspondents include: Bill Dickinson and Basil Goode.
  - Series XII. Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry Electronic Files, Subseries C. Tracey Campbell Email, 2008.
    This subseries contains 58 emails in one PST file: KaineLibtcampbell.pst. Tracy Campbell served as a Governor's Fellow in the Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry office during the summer of 2008.
    KaineLibtcampbell.pst contains 58 emails sent and received between June 2008 and September 2008.
    Subjects include: Great Dismal Swamp fires; and weekly reports from the Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Department of Forestry, and Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.
    Correspondents include: Vernita Boone, John Campbell, Shauna Chavis, Bill Dickinson, Donna Hoy, Ronald Jenkins, and Svandis Pollard.
- Series XIII. Secretary of Natural Resources Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)., Extent: 48529 emails.
  The Secretary of Natural Resources Electronic Files series documents the electronic communication of the office during the Kaine administration. This series contains 48529 emails in eight (8) subseries. Subseries have been designated for: A. L. Preston Bryant, Jr. Email; B. Nikki Rovner Email; C. Jeff Corbin Email; D. Missy Neff Email; E. Carol Denson Email; F. Bill Norris Email; G. Paula Jasinski Email; and H. Kathleen Onufer Email. There are 177 protected and confidential emails that are restricted from public access per Code of Virginia, 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to: attorney-client communications, personnel information, Workmen's Compensation claims, confidentiality agreements, and settlement discussions.
  The Secretary of Natural Resources is a member of the Governor's Cabinet, appointed by the governor, and subject to confirmation by the General Assembly. The Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for the direction of, or had jurisdiction over, the following state agencies and boards: Department of Conservation and Recreation, Department of Environmental Quality, Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, Department of Historic Resources, Marine Resources Commission, Museum of Natural History, and the Virginia Council on Indians. The Secretary of Natural Resources also served as the chairperson of the Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, and was a Board Member of the Chesapeake Bay Commission. Additionally, the Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for many smaller boards and commissions related to water control, pollution, rivers, waste management, and other environmental and recreational issues.